Guide to the Daniel Cady Eaton Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Daniel Cady Eaton papers
1854-1897
MS 581
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
6
(14 boxes)
Correspondence, writings, and other papers of Daniel Cady Eaton, botanist and professor at Yale. The correspondence is of an almost exclusively scientific nature and includes letters from a number of important scientists. Also included are some genealogical materials on the Eaton family.
Eaton, Daniel Cady, 1834-1895
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
Arranged in three series: I. Correspondence. II. Writings. III. Special Files.
Biographical / Historical
Daniel Cady Eaton, botanist, was born at Fort Gratiot, Michigan, September 12, 1834 the son of Amos Beebe Eaton and Elizabeth (Selden) Eaton. He was the grandson of Amos Eaton, a botanist. Eaton developed an interest in botany through the influence both of his grandfather, and his father, who took an active interest in the subject, though he was a military man by profession. In 1853 Eaton began the study of botany at Yale, specializing in cryptogamous plants. He graduated from Yale in 1857 and spent the next three years studying botany with Asa Gray at Harvard, specializing in the study of ferns. In 1864 Eaton was appointed professor of botany in Yale College, a position he held until his death. He married Caroline Ketcham of New York City on February 13, 1866. Among Eaton's most important published works are the section on ferns in Chapman's Flora of the Southern United States (1860) and The Ferns of North America (1877-1880). He also prepared an extensive genealogical study entitled John Eaton of Dedham, Mass. Eaton died in New Haven June 29, 1895.
The Daniel Cady Eaton Papers are divided into three series: "Correspondence," "Writings," and "Special Files." "Correspondence" consists almost entirely of letters of a scientific nature from both professional and amateur botanists. Of primary importance is the correspondence with the cryptogamic botanist William Gilson Farlow (242 letters), with the Harvard botanists Asa Gray (342 letters) and Sereno Watson (88 letters), and with John Torrey (31 letters). Other correspondents of note include: Leo Lesquereux, paleobotanist, Charles Christopher Parry, first botanist in the U. S. Department of Agriculture, William Starling Sullivant, bryologist, George Lincoln Goodale, Gray's successor at Harvard, Charles Horton Peck, mycologist, and George Vasey, expert on grasses.
The "Writings" series contains both printed material and manuscripts, each divided into two sections: "Writings" (of Daniel Cady Eaton) and "Writings of Others." A fragment of Eaton's book, The Ferns of North America, appears in "Writings" section. Among the "Writings of Others" are two published articles by Asa Gray, one manuscript of William Henry Brewer and one of Leo Lesquereux.
The "Special Files" contain genealogical material, including a copy of Eaton's work John Eaton of Dedham, Mass., and printed material.
Additional biographical material may be found in the Dictionary of American Biography.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, writings, and other papers of Daniel Cady Eaton, botanist and professor at Yale. The correspondence is of an almost exclusively scientific nature and includes letters from a number of important scientists. Also included are some genealogical materials on the Eaton family.
Botany; Ferns; Lichens; Science; Brewer, William Henry, 1828-1910; Eaton, Daniel Cady, 1834-1895; Farlow, W. G. (William Gilson), 1844-1919; Goodale, George L. (George Lincoln), 1839-1923; Gray, Asa, 1810-1888; Lesquereux, Leo, 1806-1889; Parry, C. C. (Charles Christopher), 1823-1890; Peck, Charles H. (Charles Horton), 1833-1917; Stanton, Elizabeth Cady, 1815-1902; Sullivant, William Starling, 1803-1873; Torrey, John, 1796-1873; Vasey, George, 1822-1893; Watson, Sereno, 1826-1892; Eaton family; Yale University -- Faculty
- Correspondence, 1854-1895; Series I; 4' 9 1/2" (11 1/2 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  This series is divided into two sections: "Correspondence" and "Correspondence of Others." Both sections are arranged alphabetically by name of the writer of the letter. Letters written by Daniel Cady Eaton are filed under the name of the person to whom the letter was addressed.
  Correspondents of note not previously mentioned include: Addison Brown, U. S. District Judge, New York, William Henry Brewer, professor of agriculture at Yale, James Dwight Dana, Mark Walrod Harrington, first civilian chief of the U. S. Weather Bureau, Thomas Jefferson Howell, author of Flora of Northwest America, Charles Vancouver Piper, agronomist and expert in grasses, Charles Sprague Sargent, director of the Arnold Arboretum at Harvard, Benjamin Silliman, Jr., Elizabeth Cady Stanton, reformer and woman's liberation activist, and David A. Poe Watt.
  - Abbatt, William D., 1882 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abraham, Mrs. S. L., 1868, 1870, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Adams, Thatcher Magoun, 1837-1919, 1864 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Adams, William, 1807-1880, 1874 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Agardh, Prof. Jacob George, 1813-1901, 1873-1874, 1888, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alcott, William P., 1873-1874 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Allen, Henry C., 1857 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Allen, Timothy Field, 1860-1862, 1865, 1878, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - American Association of Numismatists, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - American Express Co. (dummy folder), 1893 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    General
    See: box 10, folder 505
  - Ames, Mrs. Mary E. Pulsifer, 1875, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Anderson, Dr. C. L., 1873-1877 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Andrews, Ebenezer Baldwin, 1821-1880, 1877 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Andrews, Luman, 1839-1921, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Andrews, Dr. T. L., 1877 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Anthony, Emilie C. (Mrs. Charles), 1880-1881 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Arthur, Joseph Charles, 1850-1942, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Atherton, George Washington, 1837-1906, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Atkinson, George Francis, 1854-1918, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Austin, Coe Finch, 1831-1880, 1863, 1865-1868, 1870-1873, 1878 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Austin, Mrs. R. M., 1877, 1893-1894 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Bacon, Dr. Francis, 1831-1912, 1861 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Bagg, Mrs. Stanley C., 1878 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Bailey, Edgar Henry Summerfield, 1848-1933, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Bailey, Edward, 1877-1880 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Bailey, William Whitman, 1843-1914, 1868-1874 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Baird, Spencer Fullerton, 1872-1875, 1878 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Baker, Charles Henry, 1878, 1880, 1882, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Baker, John Gilbert, 1834-1920, 1858-1863, 1868-1869, 1877-1882 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Baker, Walter & Co., 1881 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Baldwin, David Dwight, 1831-1912, 1877, 1879, 1886 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Baldwin, Susan Elizabeth (Punchard), n.y. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Ball, The Rev. Edward Henry, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Barber, Edwin Atlee, 1851-1916, 1883 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Barbey, William, 1842-1914, 1880-1881 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Barbour, John Humphrey, 1854-, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Barnard, Frederick Augustus Porter, 1809-1889, 1873-1874 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Barnes, Mrs. Catherine S., 1875-1876, 1879 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Barnes, Mrs. Mary (Sheldon), 1850-1889, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Barnston, George, 1800-1883, 1878 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Bates, William H., 1881-1882 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Beardslee, Henry Curtiss, 1807-1884, 1878 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Beardsley, Eben Edwards, 1808-1891, 1874-1878, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Bebb, Michael Schuck, 1833-1895, 1859-1864 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Beckett, T. W. Nayler, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Belknap, William Richardson, 1849-1914, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Bell, Edward, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Bennett, James Lawrence, 1832-1904, 1875, 1879-1880 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Bennett, S. R. J., 1881 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Bessey, Charles Edwin, 1845, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Betts, Miss Emily, n.y. (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Bickmore, Albert Smith, 1839-1914, 1864 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Bicknell, Eugene Pintard, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Biddlecome, Miss H. J., 1877 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Blake, William Phipps, 1825-1910, 1867 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Bland, Thomas, 1809-1885, 1867 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Boissier, Edmond Pierre, 1810-1885, 1880 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Bolander, Henry Nicholas, 1831-1897, 1870-1871, 1873 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Booth, Miss Mary Ann, 1874 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Bornet, Edouard, 1828-1911, 1875 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Boston, A. C., 1874 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Botanical Gazette (filed in William Trelease folder), 1894 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Bourquin, Frederick, 1867-1868 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Bowles, Margaritta, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Boyd, Miss Elizabeth S., 1877-1879, 1882 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Boyd, Mrs. James R. (filed in Elizabeth S. Boyd folder), 1877 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Boyd, William K., 1893 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Bradley, Frank Howe, 1838-1879, 1870, 1872 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Brainard, Dudley S. (M.D.), 1892 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Brandegee, Townshend Stith, 1843-1925, 1871-1877, 1879-1880, 1889-1890, 1892-1893, undated (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Bray, Mrs. Maria H., 1872-1874 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Brewer, William Henry, 1828-1910, 1862-1863, 1869, 1871 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Brewster, Edward Everett, d. 1919, 1878-1879 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Bridgham, Joseph, 1892 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Britton, Elizabeth Gertrude (Knight), 1858-, 1879, 1883, 1888-1889 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Britton, Elizabeth Gertrude (Knight), 1891-1894 & Undated (Box 2, Folder 76-77)
  - Britton, Dr. Nathaniel Lord, 1859-, 1888, 1891-1893 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Brooks, Elisha, 1879 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Brooks, Henry, 1857-, 1883 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Brooks, Mrs. Oliver N., 1873 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Brooks and Co. (filed in C. Wright folder), undated (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Brotherus, Victor Ferdinand, 1849-1929, 1892 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Brown, Addison, 1830-1913, 1880, 1882 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Brown, George S., 1894 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Brown, Mary Eliz. Adams, (Mrs. J. Crosby) 1842-1917, n.y. (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Bruhin, The Rev. Thomas A., 1878-1881 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Brush, George Jarvis, 1831-1912, 1864, 1888 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Buckley, Samuel Botsford, 1809-1884, 1857-1858 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Buffalo Society of Natural Sciences (filed in Geo. W. Clinton folder), undated (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Bumstead, Freeman Josiah, 1826-1879, 1863-1867, 1870-1875, undated (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Burbeck, Miss Anna L., 1878, 1880, undated (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Burgess, Thos. Joseph Workman, 1849-1926, 1882-1886, 1888 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Burroughs, John, 1837-1921, 1881 (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - Bush, A. E., 1882 (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - Butler, Samuel Russell, 1837-1893, 1870 (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Buttre, John Chester, 1821-, 1880 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Cady, J. Cleavelend, 1876 (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Calvary, S. & Co., 1890-1895 (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - Cambridge, Mass. - Museum of Comparative Zoology, 1872 (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - Canby, William Marriott, 1831-, 1867-1869, 1873-1875, 1880-1885, 1890 (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - Canfield, Charles William, 1856-1934, 1885, n.y. (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - Cardot, Jules, 1860-1934, 1893-1895 (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - Carlton, H. P., 1879 (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - Caspary, Robert, 1818-1887, 1859-1860 (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - Cassino, Samuel Edson, 1879, 1889 (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - Cathcart, Miss Ellen Weir, 1890-1893, undated (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - Catlin, Mrs. M., 1874 (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - Chadbourne, Paul Ansel, 1823-1883, 1856-1857 (Box 2, Folder 109)
  - Chadwick, Charles Noyes, 1849-1920, 1889 (Box 2, Folder 110)
  - Chamberlain, Jerimiah Evarts, 1879-1881 (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - Chapin, Walter Henry, 1859-1937, 1890 (Box 2, Folder 112)
  - Chapman, Alvan Wentworth, 1809-1899, 1857, 1860-1861, 1875-1876, 1892-1893, undated (Box 2, Folder 113)
  - Chapman, F. W., 1890 (Box 2, Folder 114)
  - Cheatham, John A., 1880 (Box 2, Folder 115)
  - Cheney, Lellen Sterling, 1858-, 1894 (Box 2, Folder 116)
  - Cheney, Mrs. Mary B., undated (Box 2, Folder 117)
  - Chickering, John White, 1831-, 1858-1861, 1873-1876 (Box 2, Folder 118)
  - Chittenden, Samuel Hosmer, 1845-1909, 1873 (Box 2, Folder 119)
  - Clarke, Charles Baron, 1832-, 1879-1880 (Box 2, Folder 120)
  - Clarke, Isaac Edwards, 1830-1907, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 121)
  - Claypole, Edward Waller, 1835-, 1877-1878 (Box 2, Folder 122)
  - Cleburne, William, 1874 (Box 2, Folder 123)
  - Cleveland, Daniel, 1874-1876, 1878, 1881 (Box 3, Folder 124)
  - Clinton, George William, 1807-1885, 1863-1865, 1868-1873 (Box 3, Folder 125)
  - Cochrane, Mrs. H. A., 1872-1873 (Box 3, Folder 126)
  - Coffin, George W., 1879-1880 (Box 3, Folder 127)
  - Colcord, Mary (Mrs. A. D.), 1877, 1880 (Box 3, Folder 128)
  - Coleman, N., 1875, 1878 (Box 3, Folder 129)
  - Collier, Miss Hattie L., 1881-1882 (Box 3, Folder 130)
  - Collins, Clara Ely, 1834-1911, 1881 (Box 3, Folder 131)
  - Colt, Elizabeth Selden (Spencer), 1819-, 1869 (Box 3, Folder 132)
  - Comer, George, undated (Box 3, Folder 133)
  - Constable, James Jr. & Casimir, 1878-1879, 1887 (Box 3, Folder 134)
  - Cook, Edith W., 1880 (Box 3, Folder 135)
  - Cooke, Mrs. Belle W., 1879-1881, 1883-1884 (Box 3, Folder 136)
  - Cooper, Ellwood, 1829 (filed in Mrs. Sarah P. Moore Cooper folder), 1883 (Box 3, Folder 137)
  - Cooper, Mrs. Sarah P. (Moore) (Cooper, Mrs. Ellwood), 1874-1880, 1883-1884 (Box 3, Folder 138)
  - Coulter, John Merle, 1851-1928, 1877, 1881, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 139)
  - Craig, Eric (filed in Maria Louisa Owen folder), 1888 (Box 3, Folder 140)
  - Cummings, Clara Eaton, 1855-1906, 1892-1894, undated (Box 3, Folder 141)
  - Curtice, Fred C., 1881 (Box 3, Folder 142)
  - Curtis, Moses Ashley, 1808-1872, 1855, 1858 (Box 3, Folder 143)
  - Curtiss, Allen Hiram, 1845-1907, 1868-1869, 1871-1879, 1881-1886, 1894 (Box 3, Folder 144)
  - Curtiss, Mrs. F. A., 1876, 1882 (Box 3, Folder 145)
  - Cusick, William C., 1881-1887 (Box 3, Folder 146)
  - Dana, James Dwight, 1813-1895, 1864, undated (Box 3, Folder 147)
  - Dana, Mrs. Juliette Hannah (Starr), 1816-1903, 1870, 1878 (Box 3, Folder 148)
  - Darby, John E., 1857 (Box 3, Folder 149)
  - Davenport, Miss Elizabeth Wheeler, 1814-1894, 1861 (Box 3, Folder 150)
  - Davenport, George Edward, 1833-, 1873-1880 (Box 3, Folder 151)
  - Davenport, George Edward, 1833-, 1879-1883, 1885, 1888, 1890-1894 (Box 3, Folder 152)
  - Davis, Mrs. Abby L., 1875 (Box 3, Folder 153)
  - Davis, Dr. Gustavus Pierrepont, 1845-1914, 1876, 1884, 1891, undated (Box 3, Folder 154)
  - Dean, Dexter V., 1860-1861 (Box 3, Folder 155)
  - Deane, Walter, 1848-, 1888, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 156)
  - De Forest, John William, 1826-1906, 1881-1882 (Box 3, Folder 157)
  - Deming, Frederick, 1882 (Box 3, Folder 158)
  - Denslow, W. W., 1826-1868, 1866-1868 (Box 3, Folder 159)
  - Dickie, Dr. George, 1812-1882, 1871-1875 (Box 3, Folder 160)
  - Dimmick, Dr. L. N., 1874-1877 (Box 3, Folder 161)
  - Dimmick, P. J. & Dimmick, Mrs. M.S., 1874-1875 (Box 3, Folder 162)
  - Dudley, William Russell, 1849-, 1890 (Box 3, Folder 163)
  - Dusen, P., 1893 (Box 3, Folder 164)
  - Eaton, Amos Beebe (empty folder), 1806-1877, 1859, 1862, 1882 (Box 3, Folder 165)
  - Eaton, Amos M. (Box 3, Folder 165)
  - Eaton, Daniel Cady, 1873-1895 (Box 4, Folder 166)
  - Eaton, E. R. (Mrs. Edward O. Eaton), 1874 (Box 4, Folder 167)
  - Eaton, Hezekiah Hurlbert, 1829 (Box 4, Folder 168)
  - Eaton, Robert G., 1881-1884, undated (Box 4, Folder 169)
  - Eaton, Sara C., undated (Box 4, Folder 170)
  - Eaton, Thomas E. N., 1878, undated (Box 4, Folder 171)
  - Ebstein, Lt. Frederick H. E., 1873 (Box 4, Folder 172)
  - Edwards, Alfred Lewis, 1836-1910, 1875 (Box 4, Folder 173)
  - Edwards, Dr. Arthur Mead, 1836-, 1875 (Box 4, Folder 174)
  - Edwards, William, 1870, 1872, 1874 1876, 1878 (Box 4, Folder 175)
  - Eggers, Heinrich Franz Alexander, baron von, 1844-1903, 1880 (Box 4, Folder 176)
  - Elfring, Frederick, 1894 (Box 4, Folder 177)
  - Eliot, Charles William, undated (Box 4, Folder 178)
  - Engleman, George, 1809-1884, 1863, 1870, 1873-1874, 1876, 1879 (Box 4, Folder 179)
  - Essex Institute, Salem, Mass., 1873 (Box 4, Folder 180)
  - Farlow, William Gilson, 1844-1919, 1871-1874 (Box 4, Folder 181)
  - Farlow, William Gilson, 1875-1886 (Box 4, Folder 182-186)
  - Farlow, William Gilson, 1844-1919, 1887-1891 (Box 4, Folder 187)
  - Farlow, William Gilson, 1892-1894, undated (Box 4, Folder 188-189)
  - Faxon, Charles Edward, 1846-, 1879-1880, 1890 (Box 4, Folder 190)
  - Faxon, Edwin, 1882, 1891-1895 (Box 5, Folder 191)
  - Faxon, Walter, 1848-1920, 1872-1873, 1875 (Box 5, Folder 192)
  - Fee, Antoine Laurent Apollinaire, 1789-1874, 1868 (Box 5, Folder 193)
  - Fendler, August, 1813-1883, 1859, 1878-1882 (Box 5, Folder 194)
  - Fish, Fanny E., 1882 (Box 5, Folder 195)
  - Fobes, Miss P., 1881 (Box 5, Folder 196)
  - Forbes, Elizabeth A., 1882 (Box 5, Folder 197)
  - Ford, Henry C. (landscape painter), 1879 (Box 5, Folder 198)
  - Foster, Chandler & Co., 1869 (Box 5, Folder 199)
  - Fournier, Eugene, 1834-1884, 1874 (Box 5, Folder 200)
  - Fowler, James, 1829-, 1865-1867, 1871-1872 (Box 5, Folder 201)
  - Frazer, R. L. (aunt), 1869 (Box 5, Folder 202)
  - Frost, Charles C., 1854-1859, 1861-1862, 1865-1867, 1874-1876, 1878, undated (Box 5, Folder 203)
  - Fuger, Lt. Frederick, 1873 (Box 5, Folder 204)
  - Fuller, Andrew S., 1828-1896, 1869 (Box 5, Folder 205)
  - Gage, Mrs. E. W. French, 1881-1882 (Box 5, Folder 206)
  - Ganong, William Francis, 1864-1941, 1893 (Box 5, Folder 207)
  - Garber, Abram Paschal, 1838-1881, 1876-1880 (Box 5, Folder 208)
  - Gardiner, The Rev. Frederic, 1858-1917, 1878 (Box 5, Folder 209)
  - Garrison, Wendell Phillips, 1840-1907, 1874-1895 (Box 5, Folder 210)
  - Geological & Natural History Survey of Minnesota, 1882 (Box 5, Folder 211)
  - Gerard, W. R., 1875-1876, 1880-1883 (Box 5, Folder 212)
  - Gibbes, Lewis Reeve, 1810-1894, 1878-1879 (Box 5, Folder 213)
  - Gilbert, Benjamin D., 1868, 1872 (Box 5, Folder 214)
  - Gilchrist, Maude (filed in Clara Eaton Cummings folder), 1893 (Box 5, Folder 215)
  - Gillman, Henry, 1833-1915, 1869-1870 (Box 5, Folder 216)
  - Goodale, George Lincoln, 1839-1923, 1877, 1880, 1890, undated (Box 5, Folder 217)
  - Goode, Prof. George Brown, 1851-1896, 1877, undated (Box 5, Folder 218)
  - Goode, Henry, f1. 1860-1880, 1877-1878 (Box 5, Folder 219)
  - Gould, E., 1876 (Box 5, Folder 220)
  - Grant, J. M., 1873 (Box 5, Folder 221)
  - Grattann, William Henry, f1. 1873-1875 (Box 5, Folder 222)
  - Graves, Dr. Charles Burr, 1860-1936, 1883, 1889-1891 (Box 5, Folder 223)
  - Gray, Asa, 1810-1888, 1854-1859 (Box 5, Folder 224)
  - Gray, Asa, 1860-1866 (Box 5, Folder 225-226)
  - Gray, Asa, 1867-1887, undated (Box 6, Folder 227-229)
  - Gray, Jane (Loring), 1858-1859, 1862, 1866, 1885, 1888 (Box 6, Folder 230)
  - Gray (Mrs. Asa Gray), 1894 (Box 6, Folder 230)
  - Green, H. A., 1893 (Box 6, Folder 231)
  - Green, Traill, 1813-1897, 1857-1859, 1862-1863, 1868 (Box 6, Folder 232)
  - Greene, Benjamin Franklin, 1817-1895, 1860 (Box 6, Folder 233)
  - Greene, Edward Lee, 1843-1915, 1877, 1880-1881 (Box 6, Folder 234)
  - Griswold, Elizabeth, 1847-, 1872 (Box 6, Folder 235)
  - Griswold, Ellen Elizabeth, 1841-, 1872, 1875 (Box 6, Folder 236)
  - Griswold, Phebe Marvin, 1838-, 1873 (Box 6, Folder 237)
  - Gunning, Mary, 1878 (Box 6, Folder 238)
  - Guttenberg, Gustavus, 1877 (Box 6, Folder 239)
  - Hails, Abby I., 1876 (Box 6, Folder 240)
  - Haines, Elizabeth H., 1873 (Box 6, Folder 241)
  - Hale, T. J., 1860-1862 (Box 6, Folder 242)
  - Hall, Benjamin H. (filed in E. C. Stanton folder), 1892 (Box 6, Folder 243)
  - Hall, Elihu, 1822-1882, 1863-1864, 1867, 1869, 1873 (Box 6, Folder 244)
  - Hall, Isaac Hollister, 1837-1896, 1871, 1876 (Box 6, Folder 245)
  - Hall, The Rev. Jabez, 1872 (Box 6, Folder 246)
  - Harkness, Dr. Harvey W., 1821-1901, 1874, n. d. (Box 6, Folder 247)
  - Harrington, Bernard James, 1848-, 1875 (Box 6, Folder 248)
  - Harrington, Mark Walrod, 1848-1926, 1874 (Box 6, Folder 249)
  - Harris, Sarah C., 1878 (Box 6, Folder 250)
  - Hart, Miss Elizabeth, 1878 (Box 6, Folder 251)
  - Harvey, Prof. Francis L., 1878, 1880, undated (Box 6, Folder 252)
  - Haskell, Charlotte C., 1873 (Box 6, Folder 253)
  - Haskin, Maj. William Lawrence, 1841-1931, 1875-1877, 1882-1883 (Box 6, Folder 254)
  - Hathaway, Mrs. P. V., 1877 (Box 6, Folder 255)
  - Hayden, Ferdinand Vandeveer, 1829-1887, 1873 (Box 6, Folder 256)
  - Hayes, S., 1860 (Box 6, Folder 257)
  - Hedley, I. H., 1858 (Box 6, Folder 258)
  - Hemphill, Henry, 1875-1877, 1880 (Box 6, Folder 259)
  - Henderson, Capt. Frederick, 1841-1895, 1878 (Box 6, Folder 260)
  - Henderson, Louis Forniquet, 1853-1942, 1884 (Box 6, Folder 261)
  - Henry, Joseph, 1797-1878, 1860 (Box 6, Folder 262)
  - Herrick, Edward Claudius, 1811-1862, 1857 (Box 6, Folder 263)
  - Herrick, Francis Hobart, 1858-, 1886 (Box 6, Folder 264)
  - Herschell, Baron Farrer, 1837-1899, 1887 (Box 6, Folder 265)
  - Hervey, Rev. Alpheus Baker, 1839-1931, 1875 (Box 6, Folder 266)
  - Hill, Don Gleason (Dedham Hist. Soc.), 1887-1888 (Box 6, Folder 266A)
  - Hillebrand, William Francis, 1877 (Box 6, Folder 267)
  - Hillhouse, Isaphene, 1830-1904, 1883 (Box 6, Folder 268)
  - Hitchcock, Miss Mary, 1879 (Box 6, Folder 269)
  - Holden, Isaac, 1884, 1887 (Box 6, Folder 270)
  - Holt, Charles, 1846-1927, 1887 (Box 6, Folder 271)
  - Holt, Henry, 1840-1926, 1874, 1882-1883 (Box 6, Folder 272)
  - Holt, Henry & Co., 1880 (Box 6, Folder 273)
  - Holzinger, John Michael, 1853-1929, 1893 (Box 6, Folder 274)
  - Hooker, Sir Joseph Dalton, 1817-1911, 1873, 1875, undated (Box 6, Folder 275)
  - Hooker, Sir William Jackson, 1785-1865, 1857-1862, 1865 (Box 6, Folder 276)
  - Hoopes, Josiah, 1832-1904, 1872 (Box 6, Folder 277)
  - Howell, Joseph, 1876 (Box 6, Folder 278)
  - Howell, Thomas Jefferson, 1842-1912, 1880-1883, 1886-1888, undated (Box 6, Folder 279)
  - Hoysradt, Lyman H., 1874-1875, 1879-1880 (Box 6, Folder 280)
  - Hunt, Edwin, 1871 (Box 6, Folder 281)
  - Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892, 1865 (Box 6, Folder 282)
  - Huntington, Charles Phelps, 1779-1868, 1867 (Box 6, Folder 283)
  - Hussey, Prof. John, 1876-1877 (Box 6, Folder 284)
  - Hutchison, William, 1827-1885, 1882 (Box 6, Folder 285)
  - Ingalls, James Monroe, 1839, 1873 (Box 6, Folder 286)
  - Ingraham, Miss Mary C., 1872-1873 (Box 6, Folder 287)
  - Jackson, Halliday, 1817-1887, 1884 (Box 6, Folder 288)
  - Jackson, John Peter Jr., d. 1890, 1858 (Box 6, Folder 289)
  - James, Thomas Potts, 1803-1882, 1857, 1859-1860, 1863, 1865, 1868-1869, 1872 (Box 7, Folder 290)
  - Jaques, Lt. W. H., 1873 (Box 7, Folder 291)
  - Jelliffe, Dr. Smith Ely, 1866-, 1889, 1892 (Box 7, Folder 292)
  - Jesup, Henry Griswold, 1826-1903, 1869-1870, 1872-1874, 1878-1879, 1882, 1891-1893 (Box 7, Folder 293)
  - Johnson, Charles B., 1881 (Box 7, Folder 294)
  - Jones, Marcus Eugene, 1852-, 1879 (Box 7, Folder 295)
  - Judd, Albert Francis, 1838-1900, 1876 (Box 7, Folder 296)
  - Keep, Robert Porter, 1844-1904, 1870-1871, undated (Box 7, Folder 297)
  - Ketchum, Annie (Chambers), 1824-1904, 1872 (Box 7, Folder 298)
  - King, Clarence, 1842-1901, 1859 (Box 7, Folder 299)
  - Kingsbury, Alice Eliza, 1858-1937, undated (Box 7, Folder 300)
  - Kingsbury, Edith Davies, 1860-, 1872-1873 (Box 7, Folder 301)
  - Kingsbury, Frederick John, 1823-1910, 1872, 1890 (Box 7, Folder 302)
  - Kingsley, William Lathrop, 1824-1896, (1875?) (Box 7, Folder 303)
  - Kirby-Smith, Edmund, 1824-1893, 1892 (Box 7, Folder 304)
  - Kirk, Dr. Thomas, 1828-1898, 1881-1883, 1889-1890 (Box 7, Folder 305)
  - Kleeberger, George Reinard, 1849-1929, 1874-1876, 1879 (Box 7, Folder 306)